Kevin Henley

214-564-6579 | Houston, TX, 77009 | Email: kevinhenleyinfo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-henley/
Portfolio: https://kevinhenleycode.github.io/Portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/KevinHenleyCode

Summary:

Up and coming Full Stack Web Developer experienced with a wide range of technologies such as, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Node, Express and MySQL. Who loves finding the best solution to any problem. New technology is never an issue when you're always the first to learn it. A master at explanations on the highest level and the lowest. Keeping composure and staying organized in a chaotic scene is second nature. For example, during my first group project one of my teammates and I found a way to refactor our JavaScript to shorten it by over 150 lines and make it vastly more readable. I'm looking forward to being part of a high-quality team that is dedicated to making high-quality products.

Technical Skills:

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | Node.js | Express| MySQL| MacOS | Windows | Linux | iOS | Android | Microsoft Office

Projects:

Password Generator: Page: https://kevinhenleycode.github.io/Password Generator/

GitHub: https://github.com/KevinHenleyCode/Password Generator

- Generates a random password based on the user's choices
- Assumed all roles for this project
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Group Project 1: Page: https://kevinhenleycode.github.io/Group Project 1/

GitHub: https://github.com/KevinHenleyCode/Group Project 1

- Takes in two APIs and uses them together to translate text and filter unwanted words. Then takes those words and puts them through a text to speech generator that can be summoned with a button click.
- Was one of two JavaScript developers
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery/Bulma

Work Day Scheduler: Page: https://kevinhenleycode.github.io/Work Day Scheduler/

GitHub: https://github.com/KevinHenleyCode/Work Day Scheduler

- Lets the user input events for the current day by the hour. Then tells them whether the event was in the past, present or future
- Assumed all roles for this project
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery

Experience

Stock Associate

- Cost Plus World Market The Woodlands, TX
- November 2020 to Present
- Keeping the store constantly stocked and presentable for customers.

Freelance Graphic Designer

- Self Employed Frisco, TX
- November 2017 to November 2020
- Creating graphics and illustrations along with photo editing for clients.

Cashier/Lot Associate

- Home Depot Porter, TX
- May 2017 to October 2017
- A Multi-Billion-dollar home improvement retailer with more than 2200 stores worldwide.

Steering Columns/Panels/Wiring/Brackets/Setup/Shells/Fuses

- Peterbilt Denton, TX
- April 2011 to April 2016
- One of the top Multi-Billion-dollar truck manufacturing companies in the world. This is where I learned a lot about teamwork.

Builder/Packaging/Shaper/Sander/Painter/Shipping/Receiving

- Chairs 4 Worship Gainesville, TX
- July 2010 to April 2011

• A highly regarded chair manufacturer.

Courtesy Clerk/Lot Associate

- Tom Thumb Grocery Store Frisco, TX
- August 2008 to May 2010
- Part of the Safeway family. One of the most well-known grocery store chains in the US.

Education:

- Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate: Rice University (2021 Present)
 - Houston, Texas
 - 24 nonstop weeks of programming, learning the MERN Full Stack:
 HTML | CSS | Git | Bootstrap | JavaScript | jQuery | APIs | AJAX | Node | Express | MySQL | Handlebars | Sequelize | Testing | Error Handling | Heroku | MongoDB | PWAs | React
- Full Sail University (2016 2017)
 - Winter Park, Florida
 - o Associates Computer Science